

Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, C#, MVC5, ASP. Net, Web API, Entity Framework, LINQ, SQL Server, HTML, CSS, AJAX, JavaScript



Current Location: Chennai Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Highest Degree: B. Tech/B.E. [Computer Science and

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Engineering]

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, C#, MVC5, ASP. Net, Web API, Entity Framework, LINQ, SQL

Server, HTML, CSS, AJAX, JavaScript, JQuery

Verified : Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

### Summary

1.8 Years of experience in Microsoft .NET Version 4.5 development architecture.

Good working knowledge in C#, MVC5, Web API, ASP.NET, AJAX, Entity Framework, ADO.NET, SQL SERVER 2015. Development and integration of web sites.

Good knowledge in writing stored procedures and Query.

Comfortable in CMS based website development

Self-motivated, highly committed to responsibilities. Ability to work independently and with team.

Ability to quickly grasp new technologies and applications that I am introduced to.

# **Work Experience**

**Pogostick Web Solutions Pvt Ltd**, as Software Developer -Dot Net Dec 2017 to Oct 2019

**Nellai Software Solutions Pvt Ltd**, as Software Developer Feb 2013 to Jul 2014

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from Dr. Sivanthi Aditanar, Tiruchendur in 2012

### IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience
C#

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=b4c8ac1de5c60476f5a56c306b725e485a59080248465d400047410c0b...

MVC5, ASP.Net		
Web API		
Entity framework, LINQ		
WINDOWS 10		
SQL Server 2015		
HTML, AJAX		
JavaScript, JQuery, CSS		

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Tamil				

## **Projects**

Project Title: Pogostick CMS

Client: Pogostick Web Solution Pvt Ltd. Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jan 2018 - Oct 2019

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: ASP.NET4.5,C#, LINQ, AJAX ,JQuery and SQL Server 2015 MVC5 Architecture, XML

Project Details: CMS makes it easy for website editors to add new content and edit the existing content through the use of its Content Management System. The platform is built specifically for non-technical professionals, so next time a website change is required it can be processed without assistance from the IT department.

Project Title: Tailoring Management System

Client: Nellai Solution Pvt Ltd. Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Feb 2013 - Jul 2014 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: ASP.NET Windows Form, C#, ADO.Net and SQL Server 2015

Project Details: This tool helps to manage all orders/sales, customers, income, expenses, measurements, so you can keep things organised and get detailed report of your fashion business while you concentrate on other important things, it allows you to keep track of customers measurements, orders and also let you send them SMS when work is done as well as print receipts for them.

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time